coconut ice cream that's what we're
dealing with this week on Polar Ice
Creamery so let's get into something
that goes hideously wrong
so coconut ice cream I really wanted to
make a bounty ice cream bounty in
England is coconut
sweet that is covered in milk chocolate
they do a dark chocolate version which
is the same just covered in dark
chocolate in the US it what's really
close is the Almond Joys it's basically
the same thing inside covered in
chocolate but they have the Almond on
top which
we don't get over here so I really
wanted to create this bounty flavor and
I went uh on a hunt across the internet
for decent coconut ice cream recipes
and I came across everything other than
and then suddenly in a subreddit that I
follow and I'm active in someone posted
a
coconut ice cream recipe and I I've
spoke to this guy many times you know I
trust that he makes good ice cream and I
really wanted to give this one a try so
I thought I'd have a go he lives in a
very different part of the world than I
do
so many ingredients just aren't
available over here so I thought I'd
give it a bash but with what's available
in my local local supermarket
it didn't really go as planned but
I'll very briefly talk you through how I
went about this ice cream so what the
original protest for this is to start
with coconut cream whole milk whipping
cream and Frozen grated coconut now that
last bit the Frozen grated coconut I
just can't get and couldn't get so what
I used instead was creamed coconut
well I heated it all up on the stove and
then let it sit there overnight in the
fridge
after it had chilled in the fridge
overnight I took it out and strained
what was left now what came out was a
surprisingly little amount whereas the
original recipe I think would have been
very different this is where it kind of
goes a bit wrong
so I thought just for shits and gigs I'd
carry on and complete the recipe and
just see what I ended up with and so to
that I added the sugar the corn syrup I
didn't add the egg yolks because I
didn't want to change the color I wanted
this ice cream to be really white but
obviously if you add your yolks you
start to go down a yellowy kind of color
so we didn't add the egg yolks I added a
proprietary mix of stabilizers and
emulsifiers to the mix to replace those
and finally a pinch of salt
put it all on the harp heated it up to
dissolved sugars and then added in some
shredded coconut and put it in the
fridge again to chill down when I
finally when that was ready popped it in
the ice cream machine to churn when it
was right at the end of its churning
process I then did a stretchedatello
with milk chocolate with a small amount
of coconut oil added to it major it's
completely gone and looking really good
in the ice machine dished it up and this
is the result
so
alright relatively speaking but
something I did notice and I I
understand why this has happened
but first off let's try it and then
we'll see where we're at then
it tastes like Bounty it tastes like
those
shredded coconut filled coconut flavored
sweets
those little bites of chocolate
throughout there really really nice so
flavor wise it is spot on but texture
wise is where the problem is so if I let
me let me get my phone and I'll show you
what I'm talking about here
so when you get down into the actual ice
cream
it starts to become quite powdery it
starts to Fall Away
rather than be nice and smooth and this
ice cream is actually quite soft but you
see it's it's like chipping away Parts
there
now what that is it's fat
it's too much fat and that's my fault
for doing that
weirdly enough it doesn't leave a fatty
fail money inside your mouth and it
doesn't leave a fatty film on the spoon
which you get to sometimes
it tastes really good
where I went wrong was the ingredient
that is not available to me here is the
Frozen coconut flesh I looked and I just
can't get it
could I have bought coconut yes would it
have been very different to what this
other person was using yes it would have
been very different
kind of product so I used
this
creamed coconut
which is
coconut flesh that is milled down into
not not a
paste because there's still quite a lot
of coconut pieces in there
but after using it and you start looking
at the ingredients you see it yes it's
made of 100 coconut but
where the fat content of 65 after
putting that in the recipe I'll leave
that there
after putting that in the recipe
everything disappeared what I was left
with was maybe maybe 15 grams maximum of
coconut solids removing from that
original mix and you know that the
original recipe would have had basically
all of that coconut flesh come back out
so the infusion of coconut flavor didn't
work because all this traditional fat
went into the base
and from that one on it was just never
gonna work it was never going to be a
really good ice cream so
what have we done we've done it again
but without this and gone about it a
slightly different way because it's what
we've got available in our shops
[Music]
we're here on stage two
what did I want to create and that's
something actually that my wife and I
were talking I didn't want to create
just a standalone coconut ice cream
if that's what you want to achieve the
first recipe is is good to be fair
but it just wasn't what I wanted to
create I wanted to create the ice cream
version of this
and
in North America it's it's basically an
Almond Joy minus the Almond on top
and it's a really dense
I might as well just open one
if you don't know what a bounty is
there you go it's like
I'll take a picture hold on hold fire
[Music]
it is essentially there we go lots and
lots of desiccated coconut
that's all kind of squidged together
covered in chocolate that's what I
wanted to create I didn't just want a
coconut ice cream I wanted to create the
Frozen version of a bounty chocolate bar
so I made another recipe with some
different ingredients and actually the
result was okay we're gonna get some
scooped up in a minute I'll show you
but it still isn't right it's still not
what I wanted but let's get some scooped
up and I'll just explain then why it's
not what I wanted
the problem I had with the first recipe
is
the process used something very
different Frozen coconut flesh I just
couldn't find it and you know if you
live in central London maybe you might
be able to find that somewhere in Asian
supermarket but where I live it was just
a no-go
so I modified
the recipe to suit my needs my plan my
goal and
actually I've already tried this I'm not
gonna lie
the the result is really good it's
got that chocolate
stratatella it's got lots of the coconut
in it I mean it doesn't have enough
coconut I think ultimately I would need
to to add some more
desiccated coconut for for my purpose
but
you know what it's not bad at all
quick thumbnail shot while we're talking
but grab a spoon
but when you try the Bounty or the
Almond Joy
[Music]
it's sticky
coconut it's chewy
I love bounties
this the texture of this one is much
better than the first part of this video
it Scoops more traditionally
the first one was a little dry this one
it has a really unique problem
tastes like
it tastes like fake coconut
and and I don't know why
so we used this coconut milk
in the second recipe
it has
21 fat
this coconut milk in that second recipe
it has 18 fat
there is also this coconut cream
which is available
which bear with me a second
[Music]
has 22 fat
and also I bought these just because
they were there
and this one here has 15 fat
and this one has 11 fat so
excluding the cream
these are all very different fat
contents and they're not interchangeable
you're here on this channel because
you know a bit about making ice cream
and you're not just doing no churn
you're making
professional grade ice cream at home
you know now that
fat contents of your ingredients are
really important to create the right
texture that luxury grade Haagen-Dazs
Ben and Jerry's that kind of grade ice
cream that's what you're trying to
create that's why you're here that's why
you're checking out all these recipes
when you go down this route to make a
coconut ice cream that is as luxurious
as something like those Brands would
make
you can't just pick one of those up if
you pick that one up
whatever it was low teens 11 fat and
then you pick this one up at 22 fat your
recipe is going to be very very
different and that's the problem we had
in the first stage it had a really nice
taste but the texture wasn't right at
all second one much better texture
shocking flavor so
this is a failure
I mean it's a heart failure
I've created a much better coconut ice
cream or I should say a much better
Bounty ice cream
I have in turn created a much better
coconut ice cream but I need the flavor
right I need the flavor to taste like
the Bounty sweets the Bounty chocolate
bars the Almond Joys that's what I need
to create so
we're going to keep going with this and
I'm going to go through all of the
different coconut milks and coconut
creams
until I find the right combination to
give me an actual Bounty flavored Bounty
textured ice cream
I might be here a while so
if you want to see how this turns out
don't forget to like And subscribe and
hopefully we'll see you next time
the coconut conundrum continues
[Music]